- So you and Rachel tonight, huh? - Yeah.
-今晚和瑞秋有约  -对
Yeah, it's actually our first official date.
我们第一次正式约会
Wow, so tonight may be the night.
看样子今晚有事发生
You nervous?
你紧张吗
No. This is the part I'm actually good at.
不  这才是我真正擅长的部分
What must it be like not to be crippled by fear and self-loathing?
即使是恐惧和自我厌恶情绪也不能产生影响
It's okay.
对
How can you be so confident?
你怎么能这么有信心
Well, I know exactly what I'm gonna do.
因为我明确地知道我要做什么
Really? Like, you have a routine?
真的  你有个程序吗
No. See, each woman is different.
不  女人个个都不同
You have to appreciate their uniqueness.
你要欣赏到她们的特性
- Really? - No, I do six things.
-真的  -不  我会做六件事
First, I look deep into her eyes,
首先  我要深情地望着她的眼睛
then I kiss her.
然后  我会吻她
Next, I take my hand
随后我用手
and I softly graze her thigh.
轻轻地擦过她的大腿
You mean like this?
你是说这样
No, not like that. No, no. No, like this:
不是像那样  不  是像这样
I see what you mean.
我知道你的意思了
That's quite nice.
真的感觉很棒
- More foosball? - And beer.
-再来一局桌上足球  -还有啤酒
《老友记》第十季第三集 罗斯也想要褐色皮肤
《老友记》  第十季  第3集 罗斯也想要褐色皮肤
- Hey. - Hey.
-嗨  -嗨
Hey, sweetie.
嗨  亲爱的
Hey, stop staring at my wife's legs.
嘿  别盯着我老婆的腿看
No, no. Stop staring at your sister's legs.
不不  别盯着你妹妹的腿看
I'm sorry, it's just-- How'd you get so tan?
对不起  只是...  你怎么晒成褐色的
She went to one of those spray-on tan places.
她去了一个那种喷雾晒肤俱乐部
You got a spray-on tan?
你做了喷雾晒肤
Chandler gets pedicures!
钱德勒勒去修了脚趾甲
What? You do?
什么  你修了脚趾甲
Like, with the toe separators?
用那种脚趾隔离器的
Why? Why?
为...为什么
I can't believe that's sprayed on.
我还是不能相信那是喷雾晒肤的结果
I mean, it looks really good.
我是说  这看起来不错
I wonder if I should get one.
我也想做一次
Sure, then you should get a miniskirt so you can really show it off.
当然  然后你应该穿上超短裙显摆下
So do you get colors or just French tips?
你是涂了趾甲油还是只加了法式的趾甲片
- Here. Here's their card. - Thanks.
-给你  他们的名片  -谢谢
Hey, I know where this place is.
我知道这个地方
It used to be an X-rated video--
那儿曾经是个成人录影带...
Florist.
花店
- Hey. - Hey, Pheebs.
-嗨  -嗨  菲比
You won't believe who moved back to town.
你们不会相信谁搬回来了
I know. Amanda.
我知道  阿曼达
She called me too. She's the worst.
她也打给我了  她最招人烦了
Who's Amanda?
谁是阿曼达
She's this girl who lived in the building
你搬进来之前
before you did.
她也住我们那栋楼
Then she moved to England
后来她搬去英国了
and picked up this fake British accent.
还学了假惺惺的英国口音
On the machine, this is her message:
她在我留言机上的留言是这样的
"Monica, darling, it's Amanda calling."
"莫妮卡  亲爱的  我是阿曼达"
Are you trying to do a British accent?
你这是要模仿英国口音
Chandler gets pedicures.
钱德勒去美甲了
Just so I know,
我只想知道
how many more of those can I expect?
我还要受多少次这种奚落
Know what Amanda said
你知道阿曼达跟我
when she called me?
在电话上是怎么说的
"Oh, so sorry to catch you on your mobile."
"哦  很抱歉打你的手机"
If-if you don't wanna get me on my mo-Bile,
如果...如果你不想跟我在手机上说
don't call me on my mo-Bile.
那就别打到我手机上
I know. And she always brags about
我知道  她还老是拿她碰到的
all the famous people she's met.
名人来吹牛
Oh, I know!
噢  我知道
比利·乔尔:美国著名歌手
"哦...我跟比利·乔尔睡觉了"
All right, who hasn't?
好吧  谁没睡过啊
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么办
I don't wanna see her.
我不想见她
Let's just cut her out.
我们隔离了她
- What? - Cut her out of our lives.
-什么  -把她从我们的生活里隔离
Just ignore her calls
不理她的电话
and dodge her till she gets the point.
躲开她直到她明白过来
Well, I guess we could try that.
我觉得可以试试
But it seems so harsh.
不过...有点太苛刻了吧
Have you ever done that?
你这么做过吗
No. Had it done to me, though.
没  不过有人对我做过
Feels good.
感觉不错
All right, Mr. Geller, right this way.
盖勒先生  请走这边
So how dark do you wanna be?
那么你想要颜色多深呢
We have one, two or three.
我们分一二三级
Well, I like how you look. What are you?
我喜欢你的颜色  你是几级
Puerto Rican.
我是波多黎各人
Two. I think a two.
二级  我想要二级
You'll face the red light.
你要面对着红灯
When the light's on,
红灯亮的时候
the spraying's about to start,
喷淋开始
so close your eyes.
所以  闭上眼睛
When the spraying stops, count to five...
喷淋停止的时候  数五下
...pat yourself to avoid drip marks,
轻轻拍打自己防止出现液体流下的痕迹
then turn to get your back. Got it?
然后转身我们就可以喷你背后了  明白了
Spray, count, pat and turn.
喷  数  轻拍  然后转
Spray, count and pat.
喷  数  轻拍
You catch on quick.
你掌握得真快
Well, I have a Ph.D., so...
那当然  我是博士  所以...
One Mississippi, two Mississippi, three--
一只绵羊  两只绵羊  三只绵...
Wait... I'm not--I'm not finished counting!
等等...  我还没...我还没数完呢
You sprayed my front twice!
你喷了我正面两次
You never turned?
你没转身吗
No! I barely got to "three Mississippi"!
没有  我甚至还没数到三只绵羊呢
Mississippi? I said count to five.
绵羊  我是说数到五
Mississippi-less-ly?
不要绵羊
Well, how bad is it?
好吧  那这有多糟糕
Not that bad yet.
还没多糟
But it gets darker for the next four hours.
不过随后四小时颜色会变得越来越深
So how dark will it get?
那么  会变得多深
You got sprayed with two twos and--
你喷了两遍二级而且...
I'm a four?
我是四级的了
Yeah, but your back's a zero.
对  不过你背上是零级
You'll wanna even that out.
你最好让它前后一样了
Really?
是吧
You might wanna get back in there.
你可能要再进去一次
Oh, okay!
好吧
Wait a minute,
等等...
there's no light on the back wall.
后面墙上没有灯
How do I know when it's gonna start? Hello?
我怎么知道它什么时候开始  有人吗
My eyes!
我的眼睛
The same thing happened again!
同样的事情发生了
- You got two more twos? - I'm an eight!
-你又做了两次二级  -我是八级的了
Thanks for dinner.
谢谢你的晚餐
I thought you paid.
我还以为是你付的钱呢
Guess we won't be going back there.
看来我们以后再也不会去那儿了
- So... - Yeah.
-那么...  -好吧
Hey, what do you say
我们到沙发上去
we move this onto the likes of the couch?
你说怎么样
I say cheesy line, but okay.
台词够烂  不过可以
- What's the matter? - I don't know. I'm sorry.
-怎么了  -我也不知道  对不起
- I don't know why I did that. - Okay.
-我不知道为什么那么做  -好吧
Sorry.
真对不起
I'm sorry. Again,
再一次  对不起
I don't know what happened.
我不知道我怎么了
I must be nervous.
我一定是太紧张了
I don't get it. Chandler loved it.
我搞不懂  钱德勒很喜欢的
I promise. I won't do it again.
我保证...  我不会再这么做了
I really do. This is gonna be great.
真的  这次会很完美的
- Okay. - Okay.
-好吧  -好吧
Was that good for you?
你喜欢这样嘛
No, don't get it. Let the machine pick up.
不  不  别接  让答录机接
Yeah, it could be Rachel
哦  对  可能又是瑞秋
asking if someone could babysit again.
要我们帮她看孩子
- It could be Amanda. - Oh, you're right.
-可能是阿曼达  -哦  对了
I was just kidding about Rachel.
我只是拿瑞秋开玩笑的
Babysitting's a gas.
看孩子很好玩
Hello, Monica. It's Amanda calling again.
莫妮卡  你好  是阿曼达又打来电话
I'm in the neighborhood,
我就在附近
hoping I could pop by your flat.
想到你家来坐坐
You're from Yonkers!
你来自扬克斯
Your last name is Buffamonteezi!
你姓布弗玛提滋
Let's see. So should you get this directly...
看吧  如果你接到了留言
...ring me back on my mobile.
给我的手机回电话
Okay, don't hold thy breath.
好了  切勿屏住尔的气息
Hello? Is someone on the line?
喂  有人在打电话吗
Yes. I was looking for Monica.
对  我在找莫妮卡
Hang on, she's right here.
等等  她在这儿
Someone's on the phone for you.
有人打电话  找你的
We weren't picking up. It's Amanda.
我们没接  是阿曼达
I get pedicures.
我做美甲了
Hi, Amanda.
嗨  阿曼达
Actually, now is not a good time.
实际上  现在不太合适
Dinner tomorrow night?
明天一起吃晚饭
Okay, Phoebe and I will see you then.
好的  我和菲比都会到的
Why? Why? Why didn't you just say no?
为什么...  为什么你不拒绝
Well, I said no to her coming over now.
我已经拒绝让她来了
I couldn't say no twice.
我不能拒绝她两次
I got this uncontrollable need to please people.
我有种不由自主地取悦别人的需要
Fine. Fine. You would not hold up well under torture.
好吧  好吧  一拷问你就坚持不住
- Oh, and you would? - I did.
-你能坚持  -我坚持过
- Rach, are you sure you wanna do this? - Absolutely.
-瑞秋  你确定你想吗  -当然
It's just a little weird. It's you, and it's me.
只是感觉有点奇怪  是你和我
- It'll just take some getting used to. - Okay.
-我们需要点时间来习惯  -好吧
Okay, well, how can we make it easier?
我们怎么能让这个变得容易点
Okay. Let's work from the top down.
好吧  让我们从上往下来
Just work the bra, Joe.
解开我的胸罩  乔伊
Okay, got it, yeah. Absolutely.
好的  呃  明白了
- Okay. - Okay.
-好吧  -好吧
- Is this thing welded shut? - Okay.
-这玩意儿焊住了吗  -哦
All right, turn around.
好了  转个身
I gotta get a look at this thing.
我得看看这东西
Sorry.
对不起
Well, this is romantic.
这真够浪漫的
This has never happened to me before.
这种事从来没有发生在我身上
I'm an expert at taking off bras.
我是解胸罩的专家
I could do it with one hand.
我一只手就能解开
I could do it with my eyes closed.
我闭着眼睛也行
Once I just looked at one...
有一次我只看了一眼
...and it popped open.
它自己就开了
I blame your bra!
都怪你的胸罩
It's a standard issue bra clasp!
这是个标准型的胸罩搭扣
Then I blame you.
那就怪你
Yeah. That's right.
对
You threw me off with all your slapping.
是你把我的天赋都打走了
Okay, look, I'm really sorry about that, Joey.
好吧  真的很抱歉  乔伊
But do you think maybe, on some level,
有没有可能是某些层面上
you don't want to take off my bra?
你不想脱掉我的胸罩
No, I don't have another level.
我这人没有其它层面
Hold on. There's something different.
等等  有点不对劲
I went to that tanning place your wife suggested.
我去了你老婆推荐的地方
Was that place the sun?
你是去了太阳那
Oh, and it gets worse.
比你看到的要糟
Oh, my God, you can do a duet of
天呐  你一个人就能做
"Ebony and Ivory" all by yourself.
史蒂文·旺德：歌曲《黑檀木和象牙》（二重唱）
How could you mess this up?
你怎么能搞成这样
It's so easy.
这很容易呀
You go in the booth,
你进到小隔间里
count to five and turn around.
数到五  转身
How do you count to five?
你是怎么数到五的
One, two, three--
一二三...
Damn it!
可恶
I know!
我知道
What is up with Miss Hawaiian Tropic?
夏威夷热带小姐这是咋了
How was your date with Joey?
你和乔伊的约会怎么样
Well, it was good,
嗯  还不错...
until we got back to our apartment.
至少在我们回家之前
And then we were fooling around
后来我们瞎搞
and he started to put his hand up my leg...
他把手放在我的腿上...
...and I kept slapping it away.
可我却不停的打开它
You didn't like that?
你不喜欢
Well, it wasn't just me, all right?
不光是我
He freaked out too.
他也吓坏了
He couldn't even undo my bra.
他甚至解不开我的胸罩
Really? One time he just looked at my bra
真的  有一次他只看了我胸罩一眼
and it popped open.
它就自己开了
I do not know what's wrong with us.
我不知道我们怎么了
We've kissed before and that's been great.
我们以前接过吻  感觉很好啊
But this time it was leading somewhere...
可是这次  感觉不同
...and I was very aware of the fact that it was Joey touching me.
我明白那是乔伊在抚摸我
You guys have been friends forever.
你们要永远做朋友了
The first time you kissed Ross,
记得你第一次吻罗斯吗
how weird that was.
那次多奇怪
You couldn't stop laughing.
你不停地笑
You got through that.
可你也过了那个坎
Okay. That's true. That's true,
对  是这样...
we can do this.
我们能行
You're right. We can do this.
对  对  我们能行
We'll just power through.
霸王硬上弓就好
Chandler, can I talk to you for a second?
钱德勒  我能跟你谈谈吗
No need, problem solved.
没必要了  问题解决了
We are powering through.
我们来硬的
Chandler, stop. It's not going to pop open.
钱德勒  别看了  它不会自己崩开的
You don't know.
你怎么知道
- Hi, Phoebe. - Hey.
-嗨  菲比  -嗨
- Is Amanda here yet? - No.
-阿曼达来了吗  -还没
I'm sorry for screwing up
我很抱歉搞砸了
that "cutting her out" plan,
那个隔离她的计划
but I have a new plan.
不过我有了个新计划
Chandler will call in a few minutes
钱德勒答应我几分钟以后
with an emergency.
给我打个紧急电话
Okay, what kind of emergency
那什么紧急的事情
gets us both out of here?
能把我们两个人都叫走呢
What do you think of Mike and Chandler
你觉得迈克和钱德勒
being in a car accident?
出了车祸怎么样
- Are you kidding? I love it! - Okay.
-你开玩笑  我太喜欢了  -好
- Hi. - Hi.
-嗨  -嗨
Hello!
你好
It's so nice to see you.
见到你们真好
Both of you, look at me.
你们两个  看看我
Look how young I look!
看我有多年轻
Oh, gosh, we have so much to catch up on.
天呐  我们有太多的事情要分享了
But first things first. Touch my abs.
不过最首要的是摸摸我的腹肌
I don't exercise at all.
我一点儿都没锻炼
Oh, gosh. So, Monica, you're married.
天呐  莫妮卡  你结婚了
Yeah, his name is Chandler and he's--
对  他叫钱德勒而且...
Oh, smell my neck.
闻闻我的脖子
It's not perfume.
这不是香水
It's me. It's my natural scent.
这是我  这是我自然的体香
Musty.
发霉了
Gosh, this is brilliant.
天呐  这太美好了
Gosh, it's just like old times.
天呐  就像以前一样
I'm so happy you two are friends again.
真高兴看到你们俩又和好了
When were we not friends?
我们什么时候不是朋友了
Well, it was 1992.
是1992年
And I remember, because that was the year
我记得是因为那年
Evel Knievel:摩托车特技表演者
我和伊夫·肯尼上了床
We were friends in 1992.
1992年我们是朋友啊
No, I distinctly remember you were dodging her calls...
不  我清楚地记得你当时在过滤她的电话
...and trying to avoid seeing her.
还尽量不见她
You were going to cut me out?
你在隔离我
Well, kind of.
呃...差不多吧
- Oh, my God! - Oh, bugger.
-噢  我的天  -噢  见鬼
Should I not have said that?
我是不是不该说
I feel like a perfect arse.
我觉得自己就像个饭桶
Well, in America, you're just an ass.
对  对  不过在美国你只是个蠢蛋
Hello?
喂
Chandler, what's wrong?
钱德勒  怎么了
Oh, my God, are you all right?
天呐  你没事吧
Yeah, I'll be right there.
好的  我马上到
I'm so sorry, but Chandler was in a car accident.
对不起  钱德勒出车祸了
- Oh, my God. - Yeah.
-噢  我的天  -噢
- Was Mike with him? - Nope.
-迈克跟他一起吗  -没
Got the champagne?
买了香槟了
Yes. Ready to power through.
是  女士  准备好硬上了
Excellent.
太棒了
Stick it in the ice bucket,
把它放到冰桶里
the phone is off the hook...
电话线已经拔了
...and, in the interest of powering through....
为了能更好硬上
Okay, sexy...
好了  性感点儿...
...very sexy. Sexy. All right, let's do it!
很性感  好了  我们开始
Okay, you're scaring me a little bit.
好的  你有点儿吓到我了
Get over it, soldier, we gotta do this.
别怕  大兵  我们要开始了
- Okay. You like that, huh? - Oh, yeah.
-好的  你喜欢是不是  -哦  是的
You like that? Let's kick this into high gear, huh?
你喜欢吗  我们开始换到高速档
Yeah, baby! I'll show you how we do it!
对  宝贝儿  我来告诉你我们怎么做
No...
不...
You kneed me in my misters!
你顶到我的小弟弟上了
What? Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.
什么  天呐  对不起
Joey? Are you okay?
乔伊  你还好吗
Soldier down.
大兵牺牲了
We are not friends with Phoebe anymore.
我们和菲比不再是朋友了
If she asks, I protested a little, but okay.
要是她要求  我会稍稍拒绝  不过没问题
Chandler, thank God you're alive.
钱德勒  感谢上帝你还活着
Monica, can I talk to you outside?
莫妮卡  能和你到外面谈谈吗
I have nothing to say to you.
我跟你没什么可说的
My flat is twice this size.
哇  我的房子有这两个大
Please, Monica, in the hall?
求你了  莫妮卡  去走廊
Oh, that accident must have been terrible.
那场车祸一定很糟糕
You look positively ghastly.
你看着跟死人一样
Well, aren't you a treat.
你看起来太治愈了
I can't believe you tried to cut me out.
我真不敢相信你要隔离我
Why, Phoebe? Why?
为什么菲比  为什么
It was right after we were living together...
那是在我们住在一起以后
...and you were driving me crazy, okay?
你快要把我逼疯了  知道吗
You were really controlling
你什么都要控制
and compulsive and shrill.
强迫  还嗓门很高
Well, I'm still all those things!
我现在仍然这样
You're also so generous
你现在还很慷慨
and kind and scrappy.
善良  斗志旺盛
I am scrappy.
我确实斗志旺盛
Exactly. No matter what I tried to do,
是啊  无论我要做什么
I couldn't keep you out of my life.
我都不能把你从生活中剔除
Of all the people I've cut out...
在我隔离的所有人中
...you were the only one
你是唯一一个
who ever clawed her way back in.
自己找路又爬回来的
That's because I'm scrappy.
因为我斗志旺盛
Yeah, you are,
对  是的
and I'm so glad
而且我也很高兴
that you fought your way back in...
你通过斗争又回来了
...because I don't know what I would do without you.
因为我不知道没有你该怎么办
I don't know what I would do without you.
我也不知道没有你该怎么办
Well, I guess we should go back in.
我想我们该回去了
I mean, you gave me another chance.
既然你又给了我一次机会
We should do the same for Amanda.
我们应该也给阿曼达一个机会
Yeah, I guess you're right.
对  你说得对
Can you believe it?
你能相信吗
I've never had any professional dance training.
我从来没有受过专业舞蹈训练
Now, let me explain how this works.
现在我来给你解释是怎么工作的
You go into the booth and--
你走进隔间  然后...
I'm gonna stop you right there, Glenda. Okay?
就说到这儿吧  葛兰达  好吗
Does it look like this is my first time?
我看起来像是第一次吗
Now, I want four two's,
我现在想要四个二级
and I want them all on my back.
而且我想都喷到背上
Okay.
好吧
Wait. There's two sets of nozzles!
等等  这儿有两套喷嘴儿
Which one is it? Which one is it?
应该用哪一个  哪个...哪个才是
Oh, son of a bitch!
混蛋
What is the matter with us?
我们到底哪出问题了
Well, I know what's the matter with me.
我知道我哪出问题了
No, I mean with us, you know?
不  我是说我们
I mean, is it supposed to be this...
我是说  真的应该这么...
...difficult?
难吗
I don't know.
我不知道
That fake British woman's a real bitch,
那个假英国腔的女人真是个婊子
but she sure can dance.
可她真的很能跳
- Hey. - Hi.
-嗨  -嗨
Hey, listen, can I ask you a question?
听着  能问你个问题吗
When you and Monica first hooked up...
你和莫妮卡刚好上的时候
...was it weird going from friends to more than that?
超越朋友关系  感觉奇怪吗
Kind of.
有点
Sneaking around, having to hide from you guys--
到处躲藏  跟你们玩捉迷藏...
No, no, no. No, I mean...
不...  不是  我是说...
...sexually.
性方面...
Yeah, was there a part of you that felt like it was...
是不是你们俩某方面感觉...
...really wrong?
这么做不对
Actually, no. No, it felt right, you know?
实际上  不是  没有  感觉很好
If felt like,
感觉就像
"l can't believe we haven't been doing this
真不敢相信我们居然
the whole time."
早没这么做
I can tell from your expressions
从你们的表情看
that's the good news you were hoping for.
我的话对于你们来说是好消息
Well,
好吧
I'm gonna go continue to spread the joy.
我想我要去继续传播快乐了
Just because it happened that way for them
他们的反应是那样的
doesn't mean it has to for us.
不见得我们也要那样
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
对...  当然
I mean, just because something's difficult
我是说  事情困难
doesn't mean that you quit.
并不意味着你要退却
- Right, totally. - Yeah. And so...
-绝对啊  -好吧
...we'll just keep trying and trying
那我们会不停地试啊...
until we do it.
直到我们成功
If not, we'll just be
对  如果不行的话  我们就会
a couple that never has sex.
成为另一对没有性爱的夫妇
That's a plan.
就这么计划了
- I did not see this coming. - I know.
-真没相到会有这种事情发生  -我懂
I don't know, I don't get it.
那我就不明白了
I mean, I was so sure this is what I wanted.
我很确定想要这么做啊
Me too.
我也是
Well, how come Monica and Chandler could do it?
为什么莫妮卡和钱德勒就能做到
I guess they weren't
我想或许他们
as good friends as we are.
不像我们的友谊这么深吧
I bet you're right.
我想你肯定是对的
So...
那么...
Yeah.
好吧
I love you.
我爱你
Love you too.
我也爱你
- All right, I'm going to bed. - Yeah, me too.
-好了  我要去睡觉了  -好  我也是
Yeah. I'm not going anywhere for a while.
暂时我还去不了任何地方
Dude, it's Chandler. Let me in.
伙计  是钱德勒  让我进来
Go away!
走开
I don't wanna see anybody!
我谁都不想见
I know, I went to the tanning place
我也去了那个地方
and the same thing happened to me.
同样的事也发生在我身上了
You have to let me in.
让我进来
Really?
真的
Did you count Mississippi-ly?
你也数了小绵羊
You're not tan.
你没去晒
No. I just had to get a picture of this.
没  我只是来拍张照
I'll see you later.
再见